AITA for not going on family vacation unless I can
share a bed with my fiancé?... My brother and I
started planning a family vacation; first one since 2019 that
all the cousins (all adults. youngest is 24 years old)
can go. We used to rent a large beach house
every year, so we were looking at large Airbnbs that
sleep everyone and splitting costs.
On the initial call, my mom said she prefers that
my fiancé (27F) and (28F) not share a room. I
told her that wasn’t going to happen. We’ve lived together
for over two years, own a house together, and are
getting married in 6 months (3 by the time of
the trip).
We even went on a family cruise last year and
no one had any issues with us sharing a room.
For a couple weeks after that, we sent airbnb options
back and forth. No one brought up room arrangements again.
Then today, my brother tells me that my mom had
already booked a house.
When I called her, she said my fiancé and I
can either sleep in separate beds or find another place
to stay. I asked her why she didn’t tell me
earlier, and she said her original “preference” was her way
of communicating that. I told her that wasn’t a rule,
it was a preference, and I had set a boundary.
She said since she booked the house, she can treat
it like her house and set the rules. I pointed
out that we were paying our share (\~$1200), so she
doesn’t get to control our sleeping arrangements. She said we
can still pay, but we are not sharing a bed
there.
Now the cheapest option is a nearby hotel (\~$1500), which
means no kitchen and driving back and forth every day.
That’s a completely different (and more expensive) vacation than what
we agreed to. The only reason I’m even considering going
is for my special needs brother, who is really excited
about this trip. Otherwise I’d just skip it.
My fiancé is willing to sleep separately for his sake,
but I’m struggling giving in, especially since my parents don’t
support our relationship and might not even come to our
wedding. I feel stuck between paying more and giving in
to my mom’s control. I know my dad, aunt, and
grandma share the same beliefs as my mom so I
feel alone in this. AITA if I refuse to go
unless we can share a room?